Christopher Cox

U.S. Citizen
Curriculum Vitae

Science and Engineering Hall 800 22nd Street, 3rd Floor, NW Washington, DC 20052 ccox@gwmail.gwu.edu ☐ +1 (267) 567-4375 **\$**

Research Interests

My current research involves development of Huynh's high-order flux reconstruction method for solving large-scale fluid flow problems on unstructured grids using high performance parallel computing. Covergence acceleration techniques adopted include implict dual time stepping and *p*-multigridding. The current numerical solver has been used to simulate pulsatile flow of a blood-analog fluid through an idealized model of a curved artery. The goals of this work are to identify three-dimensional vortices caused by pulsatile secondary flow and correlate vortex evolution with relevant haemodynamic metrics used to assess local variation in blood flow characteristics as it relates to the progression of atherosclerosis. This work was done in collaboration with experimentalists to validate results and answer fundamental questions of the underlying flow physics. In the recent past, my research involved development of the MUSCL scheme for shock capturing as well as development of the spectral difference method for moving and deforming unstructured grids.

Education

2011-2017	The George Washington University, Washington, DC
	PhD Machanical and Agreenage Engineering

PhD, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering

Dissertation: Development of a High-order Navier-Stokes Solver using Flux

Reconstruction to Simulate Three-dimensional Vortex Structures in a

Curved Artery Model

2003-2005 **Stanford University**, Stanford, CA

MS, Aeronautics and Astronautics

1998-2003 Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

BS, Dual Aeronautical and Mechanical Engineering

Awards & Honors

2011-2017	The George Washington University Presidential Merit Fellowship
2016-2017	The George Washington University Douglas L. Jones Endowed Scholarship
2015	The George Washington University Graduate Research Theoretical Award, 1st Place
2013	ASME Pressure Vessel and Piping Outstanding Technical Paper for Fluid-Structure
	Interaction
2003-2005	Stanford University Graduate Federal Research Assistantship Award

1998-2003	Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Donald V. Edwards Endowed Engineering
	Scholarship
1998-2003	Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Dean's Scholarship
2000	Sigma Gamma Tau National Aerospace Engineering Honor Society

Pi Tau Sigma International Mechanical Engineering Honor Society

Academic Positions

2000

2011-2017 The George Washington University, Washington, DC

Graduate Research Assistant

Computational Aerodynamics and Hydrodynamics Laboratory

Biofluid Dynamics Laboratory

Advisers: Michael W. Plesniak, Chunlei Liang

Research: Development of unstructured high-order numerical methods

2005-2006 **Stanford University**, Stanford, CA

Research and Development Engineer
Hansen Experimental Physics Laboratory

Adviser: Rodney Torii

Research: Satellite test of the Equivalence Principle

2003-2005 **Stanford University**, Stanford, CA

Graduate Research Assistant

Hansen Experimental Physics Laboratory

Adviser: Rodney Torii

Research: Satellite test of the Equivalence Principle

2002 Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Experimental Fluid Mechanics Laboratory

Adviser: Amir H. Hirsa

Research: Capillary micro-switches

Teaching Experience

The George Washington University, Washington, DC

Teaching Assistant

F2013, F2016	MAE 3126 (undergraduate) - Fluid Mechanics I
F2014	APSC 6213 (graduate) - Partial Differential Equations
C2014	ADCC 6212 (graduata) Linear Algabra

S2014 APSC 6212 (graduate) - Linear Algebra

Journal Articles

- 1. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A High-order Solver for Unsteady Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations using the Flux Reconstruction Method on Unstructured Grids with Implicit Dual Time Stepping," *Journal of Computational Physics*, Vol 314, pp 414-435, June 1, 2016.
- 2. C. Liang, **C. Cox** and M.W. Plesniak, "A Comparison of Computational Efficiencies of Spectral Difference Method and Correction Procedure via Reconstruction," *Journal of Computational Physics*, Vol 239, pp 138-146, April 15, 2013.

Conference Articles and Presentations (refereed)

- 1. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A Flux Reconstruction Solver for Unsteady Incompressible Viscous Flow using Artificial Compressibility with Implicit Dual Time Stepping," AIAA SciTech 54th Aerospace Sciences Meeting, January 4-8, 2016, San Diego, CA.
- 2. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A High-order Method for Solving Unsteady Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations with Implicit Time Stepping on Unstructured Grids," AIAA SciTech 53rd Aerospace Sciences Meeting, January 5-9, 2015, Kissimmee, FL.
- 3. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Spectral Difference Solution of Incompressible Flow over an Inline Tube Bundle with Oscillating Cylinder," ASME 2012 Pressure Vessels and Piping Conference, July 15-19, 2012, Toronto, ON, Canada.
 - Awarded the Outstanding Technical Paper for Fluid-Structure Interaction

Conference Abstracts and Presentations (non-refereed)

- 1. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Correlation between Vortices and Wall Shear Stress in a Curved Artery Model under Pulsatile Flow Conditions," APS Division of Fluid Dynamics 70th Annual Meeting, November 19-21, 2017, Denver, CO.
- 2. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "High-order Numerical Simulations of Pulsatile Flow in a Curved Artery Model," APS Division of Fluid Dynamics 69th Annual Meeting, November 20-22, 2016, Portland, OR.
- 3. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A High-order Solver for Unsteady Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations using the Flux Reconstruction Method," APS Division of Fluid Dynamics 68th Annual Meeting, November 22-24, 2015, Boston, MA.
- 4. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Development of a Parallel High-order Solver with Flux Reconstruction for the Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations," AIAA Young Professional, Student and Education Conference, November 13, 2015, JHU Applied Physics Laboratory, MD.

- 5. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A Parallel 3D High-order Solver for Unsteady Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations using Flux Reconstruction on Unstructured Grids," 13th U.S. National Congress on Computational Mechanics, July 26-30, 2015, San Diego, CA.
- 6. C. Liang, **C. Cox** and M.W. Plesniak, "A High-order Compact Spectral Difference Method for Unsteady Incompressible Flow," 5th International Conference on Scientific Computing and Partial Differential Equations, December 8-12, 2014, Kowloon Tong, Hong Kong.
- 7. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "A Compact High-order Unstructured Method for Unsteady Incompressible Flow," APS Division of Fluid Dynamics 67th Annual Meeting, November 23-25, 2014, San Francisco, CA.
- 8. C. Mehls, D. Gill, **C. Cox**, N. Vora, D. Stricker, E. Berglund, P. Ambekar, R. Torii and S. Wang, "Effect of Surface Roughness on Critical Current of Niobium Films," AIP 24th International Conference on Low Temperature Physics, Vol 850, pp 991-992, September 7, 2006.
- 9. C. Mehls, C. Bayart, J. Bower, B. Clarke, **C. Cox**, D. Gill, D. Stricker, N. Vora, S. Wang, P. Zhou, R. Torii, P. Worden, D. Debra, H. Dittus and F. Loeffler, "STEP Prototype Development Status," The 11th Marcel Grossmann Meeting, On Recent Developments in Theoretical and Experimental General Relativity, Gravitation and Relativistic Field Theories, pp 2553-2555, July 23-29, 2006.
- 10. M. Vogel, P. Steen, A. Bhandar, A. Hirsa, **C. Cox** and C. Matalanis, "Bubbles and Beetles: Applications of Capillary Stability," The 1000 Islands Fluid Mechanics Meeting, May 9-11, 2003, Gannanoque, ON, Canada.
- 11. P. Steen, C. Matalanis, A. Hirsa and **C. Cox**, "Capillary Micro-Switches," APS Division of Fluid Dynamics 55th Annual Meeting, November 24-26, 2002, Austin, TX.

Poster Presentations

- 1. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Development of a Parallel 3D High-order Navier-Stokes Solver for Studying Secondary Flow Structures in a Curved Artery Model," The George Washington University Research and Development Competition, February 24, 2016.
- 2. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Development of a Fast Algorithm for Solving the Unsteady Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations," The George Washington University Research and Development Competition, February 18-19, 2015.
- 3. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "Development of a High-order Incompressible Flow Solver with Implicit Time Stepping," The George Washington University Research and Development Competition, February 19, 2014.
- 4. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "High-order Numerical Simulations of Incompressible Flow using Correction Procedure via Reconstruction," The George Washington University Research and Development Competition, February 20, 2013.

5. **C. Cox**, C. Liang and M.W. Plesniak, "An Implicit Time Marching Scheme for Shock Capturing with MUSCL Reconstruction," The George Washington University Research and Development Competition, February 29, 2012.

Industry Positions

2008-2010 McGowan Investors, Philadelphia, PA

Quantitative Research Analyst

Equity / Index Volatility Modeling for Option Pricing

2006-2008 Volare Capital Management, Philadelphia, PA

Quantitative Research Analyst

Equity / Index Volatility Modeling for Option Pricing

2001 Pratt & Whitney - United Technologies Corporation, East Hartford, CT

Design and Project Engineering Co-op

Hollow Fan Blades Department

Professional Activities

Peer Reviewer, Journal of Computational Physics

Peer Reviewer, Journal of Computers & Fluids

Peer Reviewer, AIAA Aerospace Sience Meeting

Peer Reviewer, AIAA Aviation

Member, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics

Member, American Physical Society

Session Chair, ASME Pressure Vessels and Piping Conference, 2012

Abstract/Poster Judge, The George Washington University SEAS R&D Showcase, 2018